Robert Black Papers
© 2006 University of Connecticut
Robert Black Papers.
undated, 1944-1980.
Archives & Special Collections at the Thomas J. Dodd Research Center.
Black, Robert.
4 linear feet.
The collection contains materials collected or written by Dr. Black pertaining to the geology of Connecticut, Wisconsin and Antartica.
MSS19980375
Biography
Unknown.
Scope and Content
The collection includes reprints, reviews, papers and single journal issues all on topics of interest to geology professor, Robert Black.
Arrangement
Series I: Papers ( undated, 1944-1980 ) contains reprints, papers, reviews and materials collected or written by Robert Black.
Related Material
Archives & Special Collections has a substantial collection of materials pertaining to the University, its history, administration, faculty, staff and students. For detailed information on these collections please contact the curator or ask at the reference desk.
Index Terms
This record series is indexed under the following controlled access subject terms.
Persons:
Black, Robert.
Organizations:
University of Connecticut--Faculty--Personal and professional papers.
Subjects:
Geology--New England.; Geology--Wisconsin.; Geology--Antartica.
Document Types:
Publications.; Photocopies.; Notes.
Occupations:
Educator.
Restrictions on Access
There are no access restrictions on this collection.
Custodial History
These materials were stored in Beach Hall on the Storrs Campus of the University of Connecticut for several years following the unexpected deathof Dr. Black.
Acquisition Information
The collection was transferred to the University Archives by Dr. Robert Thorson in 1998.
Detailed Description
- Series I: Papers, undated, 1944-1980
  - Northern Kettle Moraine State Forest, Wisconsin, Glacial Geol. Of-Trans., Wisconsin Academy of Science, Arts & Letters, 1969 (Box 1:, Folder 1)
  - Slopes in Southwestern Wisconsin, U.S.A.-Periglacial or temperate?, 1969 (Box 1:, Folder 2)
  - Quaternary Paleocology, A Review, 1969 (Box 1:, Folder 3)
  - Thaw depressions and thaw lakes, A Review, 1969 (Box 1:, Folder 4)
  - Patterned ground studies in Victorian Land, 1969 (Box 1:, Folder 5)
  - Glacial features of the Kettle Interlobate Moraine, eastern Wisconsin, Abstract for Geological Society of America, 1968 (Box 1:, Folder 6)
  - Ice-stagnation features of the Bloomer Moraine, northwest Wisconsin, Abstract for 14th Institute on Lake Superior Geology, 1968 (Box 1:, Folder 7)
  - Two Creeks Buried Forest Project, Journal of Geological Education, 1968 (Box 1:, Folder 8)
  - Ventifacted, Cavernously Weathered, Perched Stones of Taylor Valley, Antarctica, and the Glacial Chronology, 1968 (Box 1:, Folder 9)
  - Definition of Wisconsin an Stage, 1968 (Box 1:, Folder 10)
  - Patterned-Ground Studies in Victoria Land, 1968 (Box 1:, Folder 11)
  - Radiocarbon Dates of Wisconsin, 1967-1968 (Box 1:, Folder 12)
  - Geomorphology of Devils Lake Area, Wisconsin, 1967 (Box 1:, Folder 13)
  - Salts and associated phenomena, 1967 (Box 1:, Folder 14)
  - Patterned Ground Studies in Victoria Land, 1967 (Box 1:, Folder 15)
  - Mirabilite Deposits near the Hobbs Glacier, McMurdo Sound Area, Antarctica-GSA, 1967 (Box 1:, Folder 16)
  - Preliminary Measurements of Growth of Nonsorted Polygons, Victoria Land, Antarctica, 1966 (Box 1:, Folder 17)
  - Valders Glaciation in Wisconsin and Upper Michigan--A progress report, 1966 (Box 1:, Folder 18)
  - Patterned Ground in Antarctica, 1966 (Box 1:, Folder 19)
  - Late Pleistocene to Recent History of Bering Sea-Alaska Coast and Man, 1966 (Box 1:, Folder 20)
  - GSA--Two Creeks, Valderan, N. Kettle, 1970 (Box 1:, Folder 21)
  - Climatically significant fossil periglacial phenomena in N. central U.S., 1969 (Box 1:, Folder 22)
  - Geology, especially Geomorphology, of Northern Alaska, 1969 (Box 1:, Folder 23)
  - Saline discharges, 1969 (Box 1:, Folder 24)
  - Valderan Glaciation in Western Upper Michigan, 1969 (Box 1:, Folder 25)
  - Glacial Geology-Baraboo Range, 1970 (Box 1:, Folder 26)
  - Patterned ground studies, 1970 (Box 1:, Folder 27)
  - Landforms of cold climates, 1970 (Box 1:, Folder 28)
  - Bowser, Rafter, Black, 1970 (Box 1:, Folder 29)
  - Chronology and climate of Wisconsin and upper Michigan, 1970 (Box 1:, Folder 30)
  - Geology of the Baraboo District, Wisconsin, 1970 (Box 1:, Folder 31)
  - Pleistone Geology of southern Wisconsin, 1970 (Box 1:, Folder 32)
  - Glaciological Notes, 1960 (Box 2:, Folder 33)
  - Comparison of features on Earth and Mars, 1978 (Box 2:, Folder 34)
  - Glaciers and long term climatic change, 1978 (Box 2:, Folder 35)
  - IGCP-Conn, 1978 (Box 2:, Folder 36)
  - Clastic Dikes of the Pasco Basin, southeastern Washington, 1979 (Box 2:, Folder 37)
  - Valders--Two Creeks Revisited, 1979 (Box 2:, Folder 38)
  - Late-Quat-Sea-Level changes along the Connecticut Coast, 1979 (Box 2:, Folder 39)
  - Discussion--Shetucket, 1979 (Box 2:, Folder 40)
  - Encyclopedia, 1980 (Box 2:, Folder 41)
  - Soil Wedges, 1980 (Box 2:, Folder 42)
  - Holocene Climate changes in Aleutian Islands, 1976 (Box 2:, Folder 42)
  - Holocene sea level in The Aleutian Islands, 1978 (Box 2:, Folder 43)
  - The Winter of the World, 1980 (Box 2:, Folder 44)
  - Holocene sea level and climate in the Aleutian Islands, Alaska, 1979 (Box 2:, Folder 45)
  - Isostatic, Tectonic, Eustatic movements of sea level in the Aleutian Islands, 1980 (Box 2:, Folder 46)
  - Review--Ant. Glacial History, 1980 (Box 2:, Folder 47)
  - Comments on Periglacial Terminology, 1966 (Box 2:, Folder 48)
  - Frost action, 1966 (Box 2:, Folder 49)
  - Permafrost, 1966 (Box 2:, Folder 50)
  - Ice Wedge Casts of Wisconsin, 1965 (Box 2:, Folder 51)
  - INQUA, VIIth International Congress, Field Conference, 1965 (Box 2:, Folder 52)
  - Paleoclimatologic Implications of Ice-Wedge Casts of Wisconsin, 1965 (Box 2:, Folder 53)
  - Saline discharge, 1965 (Box 2:, Folder 54)
  - Some contributions of Wisconsin's Geologists and Soil Scientists, 1965 (Box 2:, Folder 55)
  - Saline discharge, 1965 (Box 2:, Folder 56)
  - Outline of Glacial Geology of Illinois and Wisconsin, 1965 (Box 2:, Folder 57)
  - Validity of C14 Dates in Victoria Land, Antarctica, 1964 (Box 2:, Folder 58)
  - Gubik Formation of Quaternary Age in northern Alaska, 1964 (Box 2:, Folder 59)
  - Patterned ground in Antarctica, 1964 (Box 2:, Folder 60)
  - Periglacial phenomena of Wisconsin, north central United States, 1964 (Box 2:, Folder 61)
  - Periglacial studies in the U.S. '59-'63, 1964 (Box 2:, Folder 62)
  - Physical geography of Wisconsin, 1964 (Box 2:, Folder 63)
  - Potholes and associated gravel of Devils Lake State Park, 1964 (Box 2:, Folder 64)
  - Anangula: A Geological interpretation of the Oldest Archeologic Site in the Aleutians, 1964 (Box 2:, Folder 65)
  - Pleistocene history of Bering Sea-Alaska coast and man, 1963 (Box 2:, Folder 66)
  - Hydrothermal Regiman of Patterned Ground, Victoria Land, Antarctica, 1963 (Box 2:, Folder 67)
  - Glacier Fluctuations recorded by Patterned ground, Victoria Land, 1963 (Box 2:, Folder 68)
  - Les coins de glace et le gel permanent dans le Nord de l'Alaska, 1963 (Box 2:, Folder 69)
  - Glaciation in Wisconsin, 1962 (Box 2:, Folder 70)
  - Pleistocene Chronology of Wisconsin, 1962 (Box 2:, Folder 71)
  - "Driftless Area" of Wisconsin was glaciated, 1960 (Box 2:, Folder 72)
  - Frost Action, 1960 (Box 2:, Folder 73)
  - Permafrost, 1960 (Box 2:, Folder 74)
  - Pleistocene History of Wisconsin, 1960 (Box 2:, Folder 75)
  - Glacial geology of west-central Wisconsin, 1959 (Box 2:, Folder 76)
  - Friends of the Pleistocene, 1959 (Box 2:, Folder 77)
  - Current research in glacial geology and geomorphology in west-central Wisconsin, 1959 (Box 2:, Folder 78)
  - Geology of Raddatz Rock shelter, Sk5, Wisconsin, 1959 (Box 2:, Folder 79)
  - Ice Wedges in northern Alaska, 1959 (Box 2:, Folder 80)
  - Landscapes and Earth History, 1959 (Box 2:, Folder 81)
  - Pleistocene Man in south central Wisconsin, 1959 (Box 2:, Folder 82)
  - Glacial Geology of Lake Geneva Area, 1958 (Box 2:, Folder 83)
  - Permafrost, Water-Supply, and Engineering Geology of Point Spencer Spit, Seward Peninsula, Alaska, 1958 (Box 2:, Folder 84)
  - United States Scenery, 1958 (Box 2:, Folder 85)
  - Pleistocene climatic change recorded by ice-wedge casts of Gary age at River Falls, Wisconsin (AAAS), 1957 (Box 2:, Folder 86)
  - Some problems in Engineering Geology caused by Permafrost in the Arctic Coastal Plain, northern Alaska, 1957 (Box 2:, Folder 87)
  - Permafrost as a Natural Phenomenon, 1956 (Box 2:, Folder 88)
  - Patterned ground studies in Antarctica, 1973 (Box 3:, Folder 89)
  - 59 Early racial and cultural identifications in southwestern Alaska, 1971 (Box 3:, Folder 90)
  - Permafrost, 1971 (Box 3:, Folder 91)
  - Wetland Geology, 1973 (Box 3:, Folder 92)
  - Late Quaternary sea-level changes, 1973 (Box 3:, Folder 93)
  - Ad-hoc study group on Permafrost, 1974 (Box 3:, Folder 94)
  - Origin, composition and structure of perennially frozen ground and ground ice, 1973 (Box 3:, Folder 95)
  - Wisconsin an stage, 1972 (Box 3:, Folder 96)
  - Polar Geomorphology-review, undated (Box 3:, Folder 97)
  - Perilglacial Environment, 1971 (Box 3:, Folder 98)
  - Two Creeks Buried Forest, 1971 (Box 3:, Folder 99)
  - Growth of patterned ground, 1973 (Box 3:, Folder 100)
  - Geologic evidence pertaining to the migration of the Paleo-Aleuts, 1972 (Box 3:, Folder 101)
  - Mass movement studies, 1971 (Box 3:, Folder 102)
  - Heavy Metal Wastes in Long Island Sound I/II, undated (Box 3:, Folder 103)
  - Heavy Metal Wastes in Long Island Sound, 1974 (Box 3:, Folder 104)
  - Alaska Highway Report, 1944 (Box 3:, Folder 105)
  - Mineral Deposits at Orange Hill, Alaska, 1945 (Box 3:, Folder 106)
  - Permafrost Investigations, 1946 (Box 3:, Folder 107)
  - Copper deposits, 1946 (Box 3:, Folder 108)
  - Permafrost studies, 1947 (Box 3:, Folder 109)
  - Military Geology studies in Permafrost, 1948 (Box 3:, Folder 110)
  - Review--Permafrost or permanently frozen..., 1948 (Box 3:, Folder 111)
  - Preliminary Geologic Investigations RR track..., 1948 (Box 3:, Folder 112)
  - Comments--"The study of permanently frozen...", 1948 (Box 3:, Folder 113)
  - Terrain and permafrost, 1948 (Box 3:, Folder 114)
  - ARL Lecture, 1949 (Box 3:, Folder 115)
  - Oriented Lakes of northern Alaska, 1949 (Box 3:, Folder 116)
  - Permafrost, 1950 (Box 3:, Folder 117)
  - Barrow Conference, 1950 (Box 3:, Folder 118)
  - Comments--Glaciological research as related..., 1951 (Box 3:, Folder 119)
  - Eolian deposits of Alaska, 1951 (Box 3:, Folder 120)
  - Permafrost, 1951 (Box 3:, Folder 121)
  - News release--Ice wedges, 1951 (Box 3:, Folder 122)
  - Quaternary time units, 1952 (Box 3:, Folder 123)
  - Polygonal patterns and ground conditions, 1952 (Box 3:, Folder 124)
  - Engineering bibliography, 1953 (Box 3:, Folder 125)
  - Alaska RR, 1953 (Box 3:, Folder 126)
  - Review--Permafrost, 1953 (Box 3:, Folder 127)
  - Review--Permafrost, 1954 (Box 3:, Folder 128)
  - Precipitation at Barrow, 1954 (Box 3:, Folder 129)
  - Permafrost and ground water, 1955 (Box 3:, Folder 130)